VARNA VINCENT

394 Boynton Ave, Apt B-10, San Jose, CA 95051 6692046244, varnamvmv@gmail.com

SUMMARY

A passionate developer with four years of experience developing web and mobile applications in vacation rental and healthcare domains. Known for strong technical, analytical and organizational abilities. Excellent team player with strong work ethic and personal integrity. Strong technical expertise in the latest web and mobile technologies and comfortable following the agile practices.

SKILLS

- Strong: Core Java, Javascript
- Intermediate: Git, VueJs, PHP, Laravel, HTML5, Ionic framework, Apache Camel, REST, SOAP Webservices, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, AngularJS, XML, XSLT, AJAX
- Familiar: Spring, Oracle, Maven

SIDE PROJECTS

 Number Sense Game - An interactive game to help you visualize numbers and develop your number sense.

EXPERIENCE

Nibodha Technologies, Infopark, Kakkanad (2015 - 2016)

Senior Software Developer

Care Services [May 2016 – July 2016]

- Mobile app that helps the general practitioner to find nearby community services for patients
- Tools used: AngularJs, Ionic Framework, Firebase, Git

Always On Vacation [January 2016 – May 2016]

- Contributed to developing a framework for bulk data processing Databridge
- Developed APIs and integrated modules from vacation rental property suppliers
- Tools used: Core Java, Maven, Apache Camel, Jenkins, Spring, MongoDB, MySql, Oracle, Git

Mobile Insight [October 2015 – December 2015]

- Developed a highly scalable messaging module
- Tools used: Core Java, Maven, Git, Jenkins, Spring

Sos [March 2015 – September 2015]

- Developed a responsive admin website, tablet app and a cross-platform mobile app for the SWAT team and employees in an organization to be used in the event of a catastrophe.
- Tools used: Angularjs, javascript, Parse db, Ionic framework, Bootstrap, Grunt, Yeoman

Zerone Consulting Pvt. Ltd., Infopark, Kakkanad (2012 - 2015)

Software Engineer - Level 3

Acer Web Development [November 2013 – March 2015]

- Led a team of 3 engineers to enhance ACER's Australian site for their distributors and retailers.
- Developed additional modules for budget forecasting and special pricing for bulk demands.
- Enhanced existing modules to facilitate the claim process between Acer's customers and the various business units within Acer.
- Tools used: Java, Servlets, Spring 2.0, XML, XSLT, Oracle db, Maven, JBOSS server, HTML, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX

HealthFabric - Tablet [January 2013 – October 2013]

- Contributed to the development of HealthFabric, a tablet based solution, allowing patients to record their health and social care information.
- Have moderate expertise in development of the switchyard application routing web services between HealthFabric and SugarCRM
- Tools Used: Phonegap, jQuery, Ajax, SQLite DB, Switchyard, JBOSS, REST, SOAP web services, Core Java, Maven

Data Scrapper [August 2012 – December 2012]

- Involved in a team of five, in extracting data from various healthcare congress meeting abstracts.
- Tools used: Microsoft Excel 2013, VBA, Macro

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

• Currently developing a website for a non profit organization in Arizona, <u>Collaborating for a Cause</u> using PHP, Laravel, PostgreSQL.

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Computer Science and Engineering, 2008-2012

TocH Institute of Science and Technology, Arakkunnam

EXTRA CURRICULAR

- Master of ceremony at technical conferences hosted by MobConf.
- Active member of MobConf Technical Community.
- Coordinator of events at Nibodha Technologies and Zerone Consulting.
- Member of Entertainment Committee at Zerone Consulting.